

# **Profile**

Cloud and Content Delivery Network expert, Computer analyst with strong communication, leadership skills, and strong technical background.

Used to frequent customer contact, working with people from diverse backgrounds and responsibilities. I handle pre-sales, implementations and used as a point of escalation as the technical expert. Lead on calls with customers, demos, on-site training, Conferences, QBR's, Architecture reviews, etc.

I am capable of working under pressure and in a multinational environment where the proactive and fast learn competencies are vital to ensure the work is done with the best quality possible.

# **Employment History**

#### Enterprise Architect, Akamai Technologies, San Jose

JULY 2020 - PRESENT

The Enterprise Architect (EA) is a technology leader who provides technical advisory services to key decision makers, and provides design services for the technical development and integration of solutions for enterprise customers based on Akamai's Intelligent Edge Platform.

The role serves as the ultimate technical authority during a project, from scoping to customer sign-off. The EA is involved early in the pre-sales cycle to determine feasibility of complex solutions, help qualify leads for value-added consulting opportunities, support with the scoping effort and ultimately help the Akamai sales teams grow their business in top tier accounts.

The EA shows high standards of leadership – provide subject-matter-expertise for new products to the rest of the organization and actively develop junior staff within the Global Services and Support organization through training and one-on-one mentor-ship.

Main ares of focus:

- Consulting with customers on their DevOps strategy and educating & building tools to include Akamai in our customer's pipeline
- Web performance consulting including the use of data science capabilities for mPulse.

### Enterprise Architect, Web Performance, Akamai Technologies, San Jose

JULY 2018 - JULY 2020

Architect/Design and document complex solutions (Infrastructure, Web Performance, Zero Trust, Availability, etc) that require the participation of multiple organizations

Provide consulting services to key decision makers and designs for the development of enterprise customers. Analyze site performance and business effectiveness of web sites, mobile web sites, and mobile apps, with a focus on helping customers optimize their sites for maximum conversion and revenue through the use of tools like DataScience. Acting as the highest service escalation point for platform and production performance issues.

Build strategic roadmaps with customers to meet their business objectives and

### **Details**

+506 8712-3196 roymartinezblanco@gmail.com

#### Links

Personal Blog

Linkedin

# **Skills**

**Content Delivery Network** 

Amazon AWS| Google CP

DevOps

Data Analysis

**Computer Programming** 

**Cloud Computing** 

# Languages

Spanish; Castilian

English

### **Hobbies**

Photography Hiking achieve increased value from their investment in Akamai.

Establish a high standard of leadership – provide subject matter expertise for new products to the rest of the organization, and research, establish, and disseminate industry trends.

#### Senior Solutions Architect, Akamai Technologies, San Jose

MARCH 2017 - JULY 2018

SME for web delivery products and web optimization because of this I work with product teams to drive their projects, usually the sought out person to work on a new release/product/beta and go to person for high complex scenarios without the need of much scoping since capable of thinking outside of the box. Team lead for local and global solution architects, and documentation evangelist for multiple products. Constantly creating custom solution/implementations that are outside of the scope of our products but within the capabilities of the platform and because of this I implement this solutions on advance logic/Metadata to meet our customer expectations.

#### Solutions Architec II, Akamai Technologies, San Jose

SEPTEMBER 2015 - MARCH 2017

As a experienced SA II was constantly training new hires, as well doing onsite customer visits to train them on any product and even delivering custom topics. Any complex implementation or unknown environment that had challenges to have it implemented within the platform was owned and passed on to me. As well major accounts that required a lot of expertise and carefulness due to the contract that had in between was passed on to Senior SA and me. Constantly collaborate with cross functional teams to prepare documentation and proactively work towards the mitigation of identified risks and roadblocks.

#### Solutions Architect, Akamai Technologies, San Jose

JULY 2013 - SEPTEMBER 2015

As a Solutions Architect I am part of the Akamai Service Delivery team and work directly with clients to deliver Akamai's solutions. Being involved with projects from requirements gathering, design, implementation, testing and customer sign-off. I usually work independently or within a global technical team in delivering the appropriate solution to Akamai's customers. The day to day includes plan, implement, test, and deploy Akamai platform configurations to integrate our customers' web sites with the Akamai Intelligent Platform, develop and execute test cases and scripts for customer solutions.

#### Responsibilities:

Work as a member of a cross-functional project team contributing to the technology-based solutions and consult on concept feasibility.

- \* Own the technical components of a customer integration project including but not limited to design, configuration, debugging, documentation, testing, and go live support.
- \* Integrate Akamai's Solutions including media, acceleration, downloads and security products.
- \* Partner with Business Support, Sales, Engineering, Product Development and Customer Care to resolve issues that arise during customer trials, integrations, or post implementation support.
- \* Identify technical risks and provide mitigation strategies.

### Operations Support Engineer, Hewlett Packard, San Jose

As DevOps Engineer my work was focused on process automation. This meant developing software that was used by the support staff and managers. The software facilitated and increases productivity, for the BU (Enterprise Storage, Servers and Networking). Thanks to the development we were able to capture metric data to create reports that was provided to Senior management and to the agents as their score cards. This meant that I also maintained all Application servers, Databases, managed communication to the staff of all levels about all news or activities about the tools developed and also owned all project management activities. All software's developed were done with .NET due to HP's alignment to Microsoft products.

### Disk Storage Engineer, Hewlett Packard, San Jose

APRIL 2010 - JUNE 2012

Hi-complex with various operating system (HP-UX, OpenVMS, WSS 2k3 /2k8) supporting storage servers, disk enclosures, switches, Hardware and software. Knowledge in different protocols fiber channel, SAS, SCSI and ISCSI etc.

Designed websites to facilitate and increase productivity of the team. Trained/Mentored new Engineer's

#### Co-Founder/CTO, Dreamplay Costa Rica, San Jose

JUNE 2016 - DECEMBER 2018

Leading an amazing and energetic team on building Virtual Reality professional services.

Research and Development on how this technology can improve people's life in the area of healthcare.

# Education

#### Systems Engineering, Universidad Americana, San Jose

JANUARY 2010 - JANUARY 2014

# Courses

#### Certified Solutions Architect - Associate, Amazon Web Services

DECEMBER 2018 - DECEMBER 2021

#### Splunk Certified

DECEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

#### Core Administration Certification. Red Hat

JUNE 2013 - JUNE 2015

#### Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services

JULY 2018 - JULY 2021

# References

References available upon request